There's been a lot of misinformation
about AI.
>> This is Andrew. He co-founded Google
Brain and Corsera. His machine learning
course has reached millions of learners
and he is one of the most influential
voices in AI today.
>> So, a handful of leading AI companies
have been very loud voices of fear
monongering around AI to try to get
regulations passed. This drum beat of
fear-based messaging has skewed [music]
societal perception to be really
negative on AI. People talk to me about
data centers and job loss.
>> Maybe AI could do 30 40% of many jobs.
And what that means is well that 60%
that the human does has become even more
valuable.
>> What about loss of human control over
AI?
>> I think about something else that we
can't control.
I think you're one of the voices in AI
who comes with a huge background in
machine learning and teaching AI and
also you're a positive voice because
this is something that I've been seeing
especially this summer how poor the
society has become especially on social
media when I'm posting about AI and
people talk to me about data centers and
job loss. Why do you think this wave
started recently? What do you think the
causes are? There's been a lot of
misinformation about AI and the root
cause of a lot of this is an unfortunate
attempt that started two three years ago
of I think PR and regret capture. It
turns out that the most one of the most
valuable things in AI right now is the
giant AI models, giant large language
models that some have trained. But if
you spend billions of dollars training a
model is really inconvenient if someone
else trains a model and wants to give it
to anyone in the world to use for free.
So, a handful of leading AI companies, I
think, as you know, have been very loud
voices, fear-mongering around AI to try
to get regulations passed to create an
unfair playing field that favors
incumbents so that we all have to pay a
high toll for use of AI while stying the
other teams, be it researchers or other
companies that want to just give away
open way to open source models that
anyone could use much cheaper.
Unfortunately, fear-mongering works. Um,
when you go and say AI is like nuclear
weapons, which is an analogy that has no
basis in fact, what do they have to even
do with each other? Or when you go
around and cherrypick cases of AI, you
know, making a misstep and making it
much bigger than it is or even spread
misinformation about how AI uses data
centers, uses a lot more water than the
actual reality. This drum beat of
fear-based messaging has skewed societal
perception to be really negative on AI,
which is unfortunate because this is
slowing down American adoption in AI.
This is making America less competitive.
Um, and unless we get the truth about AI
out there, which is that it's fantastic
benefit with some problems, but not
nearly the TV which they're blown up to
be, it will um will hurt individuals.
>> I'm going to read out some of the
problems that people are highlighting.
Job loss and inequality. What do you
think?
>> The job apocalypse or job apocalypse,
this idea that AI will take over 50% of
jobs, people will be out of work, riding
in the streets, that's just not going to
happen. With every wave of technology,
including AI, [gasps]
the skills we need to do great work
shifts. And so AI is changing job
professions. But boy, I wish AI were AI
just doesn't work well enough. I know
that handful of businesses want to hype
up AI to say we have super intelligence
or we have artificial general
intelligence or whatever and can do all
the stuff that humans do. I wish AI work
better. We're just not good enough to
make AI do everything a human does. And
if you look at the analysis of jobs,
economists uh like my friend Eric
Brennoffson at Stanford, Andy McAfee at
MIT, um economists have analyzed many
people's jobs and by break it down into
individual tasks and maybe AI could do
you know 30 40% of many jobs and what
that means is well that 60% that a human
does has become even more valuable
because it's called an economic
complement to the 30 40% that's now
cheaper and So what will happen is
people that use AI, maybe people that
use AI will replace people that don't
use AI, but AI is not in a position for
the vast majority of jobs to replace
people. Of all the different
professions, the one that's most
affected by AI now is software
engineering because AI is actually
fantastic at writing code. And
[clears throat] what we see is that the
number of job openings in software
engineering is up contrary to what you
know the doom fear-mongerers would say
right AI is not actually able to replace
software engineers and all the good
software engineers I know are busier
than ever now the flip side of it is if
someone still write code like is 2022
before chai GPT they're in trouble they
need new skills like don't don't do
stuff that that 30 40% AI can automate
you got to stop doing that let AI do
that but then gain your skills to do the
other 60 70% that AI cannot do.
>> What would your advice be to new
graduates? Cuz I talked to Eric um on
this podcast and uh he was talking about
that there's not really a lot of impact
on the job market except for I think he
mentioned people from 18 to 25 who just
graduated. What would be your advice to
those people who don't have the
expertise maybe to strategize in their
job yet? uh they can only do manual work
that AI can do as well.
>> So one real challenge um uh for fresh
college grads is that the university
system is slow to adapt and so um you
know I love academia. I think we should
all support academia and universities.
And when AI comes and transforms the way
software is written, universities often
take like a year or two for the faculty
to master skills, then create new
courses, get curriculum committee
approval, whatever, get the faculty
senate to vote. It just takes years. And
that speed of change in academia is very
poorly matched to the speed of change in
AI. So sadly, many universities are
still teaching students to be ready for
the jobs of 2022 when we shouldn't even
be teaching them for the jobs of 2026.
We should be teaching them for the jobs
of 2028 and beyond. And what this means
is the job openings are there. Uh tons
of employees I know just can't find
enough skilled, you know, uh people at
any level of seniority. But um it turns
out in my office right now, we have a
lot of interns. There are current
college students, fresh college grad. We
also had one high school intern and
they're amazing and productive. But the
key is they're all very AI native. They
all use AI tools to do the things AI
could do, but then also, you know, lean
in to doing the things that uh humans
can do that AI can't for the for for a
long time. So there's plenty of work for
people to do. But so my advice to fresh
college grads or the people currently in
college is um by all means work hard in
classes. you know, get good grades,
learn from the instructors, but to the
extent that there's still additional
skills that the university has not yet
adapted to teaching, then find other
ways to learn online, be it from Corsera
or Deep Learning.AI or Udemy or other
places where you can gain the more
cutting edge skills, especially AI
skills that um universities have not yet
worked in the curriculara.
>> Quick pause because what Andrew just
said about workflows connects to
something that HubSpot just put out for
free. The thing is the real opportunity
right now is not just in the models
themselves, but in what you build on top
of them. How you turn AI from a chat
window into workflows that actually do
work for you. And the good news is you
don't have to start by building a full
agent. You can start much simpler with
better prompts. HubSpot just released
the advanced chat GBT prompt engineering
playbook. And the idea is very simple.
in 7 days. It helps you move from
getting generic AI answers to building
prompts that give you much more
consistent and useful options because
we've all had this moment. You type in
one vague sentence, get something
mediocre back, and then spend the next
20 minutes fixing it yourself. This
playbook is basically built for that
exact problem, and it walks you through
a single progression. First, you learn
how to structure prompts with things
like role, context, format, and
parameters. Then it gets more advanced.
Few shot examples, chain of thought
reasoning, more precise prompt
structures, and ways to make outputs
more reliable. What I like is that it
doesn't stop at individual prompts. It
also shows you how to build reusable AI
personas, modular prompt components, and
eventually your own signature prompt
engineering system. So instead of
starting from scratch every time, you're
building a repeatable way to work with
AI. Whether you're creating content,
analyzing data, or making business
decisions, the playbook is free. Links
in the description. Thanks to Hopspot
for sponsoring this video. And now back
to our conversation with Andrew.
>> I want to say one other thing. Um it
turns out one if if look at the skill
map changes. One of the most important
changes is um it's so much easier to
build with AI than before. When
something becomes much easier, a lot
more people should do it. And so now,
not only should professional software
engineers build software with AI, it's
becoming much easier for everyone to
build with AI and people that embrace
that and do so will be more productive
and will accomplish more and I think
have more fun than the ones that don't.
And AI lets you build really fast. So
for people that not just software
engineers but you know marketers,
recruiters, uh HR professionals,
operations specialists, I think if they
learn to build with AI, uh they'll
really just do much more whatever their
job row is.
>> How do you by the way measure uh the
increase in productivity uh when you
deploy AI? Do you have like a KPI in
your company?
>> I wish a simple answer. I find that the
business outcome of AI is more a
function of the business than a function
of the AI. For for some it may be um
increase you know uh customer growth and
retention or maybe faster to serve
customers or increase accuracy in some
tasks. So the KPIs tend to be related to
the business rather than the AI. M so
you can't like directly measure just AI
because it's it's an interesting thing
to do because we've been deploying AI
actively in my company and I think for
me as a media company it's probably the
amount of views the output [snorts] uh
it's just interesting how yeah it's just
interesting how different people measure
even revenue like if you're becoming
more effective
>> uh with um how you make money
>> actually same how are you using AI in
your business
>> oh my god I have the so first of all we
have claude for all of us and we have
certain projects for every social media
that we're on so for example for this
podcast. We [snorts] have a project
that's called guests and it knows all
the analytics from previous guests and
it has certain criteria on which we rank
every single person who comes to the
podcast whether he's he or she's cited
whether they have a certain opinion on
AI whether they've been active with AI
in their company or if they're a recent
founder in AI. So it gives them
different weights and it comes up with a
grade based out of 40. 40 meaning tier
one, 30 meaning tier three, etc. And
then we have another one that analyzes
every single podcast and gives me tips
on how to ask questions.
>> Oh wow.
>> Same for Instagram, same for LinkedIn.
It has my tone of voice, personal
dossier, my business strategy. So it
whenever it writes something, it knows
all the facts about me, how I sound.
Every social media is run by a person.
So a person makes a strategic call and
by the way if you can give me feedback
on this if I can improve. So what I'm
working on right now is closing the loop
because sometimes they send me a text.
I'm like oh we need to change this this
and that. But that happens in a chat in
Telegram and we have this feedback. We
we have a bot that scans all of our
chats. But I really want AI to be able
to learn continuously from this feedback
to just know my taste better. There's
one thing I see a lot in AI which is um
it turns out for AI as data scientists
or AI brainstorming partner it often
comes up with you know one or two good
ideas two or three mediocre ones and
like you know four atrocious ones and
sometimes you wonder how could my AI
have thought you know like that could
even be a plausible idea and to me this
relates to the job apocalypse point of
view which is that for a long time
humans you me everyone watching this
will have a significant context
advantage over AI, which is that you
know something that's incredibly obvious
to you that you know that was an awful
idea but the AI did not and it turns out
that one of the reasons why AI will not
replace our jobs or whatever of large
business anytime soon is because humans
have a massive context advantage
compared to AI. We know so much that you
know from our years of experience that
we talked to customer we saw the funny
facial expression that told us ah they
don't like this or we talked to business
or you know our manager said hey blah
blah blah I really care about this and
so it turns out that almost all humans
well maybe all humans just know a lot of
stuff that the plumbing does not exist
and I don't think exists for the
foreseeable future for AI to get I know
sometimes people talk about the
importance of human judgment or human
taste and Some people wonder all right
what is taste is this fuzzy thing but to
me the technical thing that underlies
why humans have better judgment and
better taste than AI is this context
advantage and because this is a
long-term advantage like no one's going
to solve this you know in a few years
this is why we just need a lot more
humans with that judgment and taste to
keep on complimenting AI
>> and doesn't this make education even
more important because education gives
us context because it's another another
thing I'm hearing about AI like you
won't need education because all the
information is at your fingertips. You
just ask Chad GPT. But when you say
context and taste, for me, that's years
of acquiring knowledge and learning from
the best and seeing how they perform
versus just asking a chat.
>> I'm going to say something that may be
controversial. I don't know I've said
this publicly, but I think it's true,
which is frankly AI models are terrible
for learning. Um, I know people think
AI is AI is wonderful at getting things
done. use it all the time, love it. But
all the data that's coming out is that
when say college students use AI, we
know this. It's just a study now back up
as well. So we also have numbers. But
the data is very clear. Students score
higher on homeworks when they use AI.
Yay, higher homework scores. But
retention, their long-term performance
is much worse because their AI do the
work for them. more and more studies are
coming out to back this up now that I
think people think oh it turns out you
know I think Wikipedia is a wonderful
tool has tons of facts web search is a
wonderful tool has tons of facts but it
turns out that when you ask AI to do
work for you you're cognitive offloading
to AI which is great because that's how
society moves forward and gets work done
but human retention is much worse it's
just so clear that LMS MS as they are
most commonly used are terrible for
learning. I'm not saying there's no way
to use it in a way that is good for
learning. I think there are ways to use
that good for learning but even for
myself there's so many things on the AI
model over the last you know 6 months or
whatever like I don't know [gasps]
building some project how does this
front end backend component work
whatever give me the answer get the job
done it was fantastic but 6 months later
I don't remember the answer when I need
to redo that front end backend component
I ask AI again so data is really clear
we should stop thinking of AI as helpful
for learning at least the vast majority
of ways that the vast majority majority
of your people are using AI models
today. It's absolutely terrible for
learning.
>> But you're building a company helping
solve that, right? Because the one
onetoone tutoring with AI is that where
you just announced with a 100 million
investment from Corsera.
>> Yes. So I'm excited about leading a new
organization called Learn Vector that is
focused on um building new learning
experiences that is much more onetoone
than one to many. So you know 15 years
ago I I was privileged to participate in
the online courses movement that I think
changed the way a lot of people learn
but that was and still remains largely a
one to many experience where everyone
you know kind of watches the same video
which is actually okay it actually works
well but the technology now exists to
create much more personalized customized
onetoone experiences and so our team is
working hard on that I think we'll have
a lot more to show by early next year
when think about human skill
development. I I feel like because AI
has so heavily impacted software
engineering, um what we see happening in
the job market for software engineering
is a harbinger as a forerunner of what
we'll see in other disciplines as well.
And in software engineering, um people
need to learn new skills, but when they
do, they are thriving and creating more
value and frankly getting raises and
doing even more exciting projects. And
what I've seen the early signs of in
other disciplines as well for example in
software engineering you know most
developers like front end backend
developers have now become full stack
developers because of AI hub you could
take on broader scope I'm seeing early
signs of this in other disciplines as
well where for example someone that in
marketing that did marketing
coordination uh coordinating marketing
campaigns with AI help they can now
become more of a full cycle marketing
take on a broader scope and I'm seeing
you know frankly sources in recruiting
become more full cycle do endto-end
recruiting. So now the good news and bad
news is for people to step up to these
broader roles. You do need to learn AI
skills but also it's not just learning
AI you also need to learn these other
skills uh like how do you do the other
parts of marketing of recruiting or
software engineering or AI engineering.
So I think this actually creates a heavy
need, a big need for people to gain new
skills. But when they do, which is both
AI skills, but also disciplinary skills,
then they can do much more, hopefully
have more fun, work on more exciting
projects, hopefully get paid more as
well. And one reason I kind of worry
about the fear mongering is um I got an
email from someone that was about to
enter college and you know he emailed me
saying hey Andrew taking online courses
but I'm really struggling with what I
should major in college because in four
years won't AI do all this and
everything I learn will be obsolete and
the answer is no of course it won't all
be obsolete but when we keep on pushing
these fear messages uh we make people
wonder if they will even be relevant and
it makes people not lean in to gain
these skills, they'll put them in much
better position. So, I see very clearly
that these fear-mongering messages are
distorting how many people, including,
you know, high school students, college
students, fresh grads, think about the
economy. And frankly, making people give
up is one of the worst things we'll be
doing in this era when people that lean
in will thrive.
>> Andrew has taught over 8 million people
AI. He started teaching machine learning
online back in 2011, years before the
current AI boom. Now, one of the
companies he's building is focused on AI
agents. From the way that it sounds, it
can still feel way too technical. So, I
put together a step-by-step guide to
building your first AI agent with no
coding required. It walks you through
what to automate, how to set it up, and
how to make it actually useful. It is in
my newsletter this week. The newsletter
is called Future Proof. It's free. Link
is in the description. What would you
reply back to that email that somebody
sent you? What would you say is the best
major to study now to thrive in AI era?
Do you think it's like going deep into a
niche or just broader computer science
so that you can acquire AI skills really
fast?
>> You know, I don't know what's the best
major. There are awful lot of great
majors. It's is like um I kind of feel
like what's the best job in the world is
like what's the best major in the world?
>> Oh, something that you love, right?
>> Yeah. My daughter wants to be an
astronaut. I don't know if she can major
in becoming an astronaut. I have to
think about that. When she get older
though, she may change your mind. I see
so many opportunities um across across
so many job roles. It all seems very
exciting to me. But do learn AI, do
learn to build with AI. The other thing
that my team's been working on AI
engineing skills map to try to map out,
you know, the most important skills for
AI engineering. One thing that I felt
intuitively, but I was surprised to see
it show up in the data was that a lot
more job descriptions seem to be saying
they want people that demonstrate a very
high sense of agency. Because it turns
out with AI there a lot more
opportunities for individuals to spot
problems and go build something or do
something to go solve it. So I think
we're really evolving. Well, we've long
been evolving but we're accelerating
positive era where people sit around and
wait for their boss to tell them what to
do.
>> This is what I've been feeling a lot
especially when we started doing remote
work. I want people to be entrepreneurs
within their niche. Like if you're
helping me with LinkedIn, you're an
entrepreneur there. You can hire more
contractors. You can deploy different
tools. You make the strategic decision
whether this topic is good or not. Shall
we proceed with it? I really think and
tell me if you agree with me, we're
moving into that job market where
everyone is kind of independent in their
workplace.
>> I think people will have much more
autonomy and creativity. So I agree with
that. And I'd even go one step further
which is I talked to a lot of people is
know engineers and others in large
companies that tell me that their
manager tells them to stay in their swim
lane. They'll say, "Oh, I have this
creative idea, but the manager says,
"No, I need you to focus on this one
thing, frankly, often because their
manager's career depends on it." But I
feel like the number of opportunities
for people to spot things outside the
swim lane. Um, and then in a responsible
way explore how to get it done, that
feels very exciting to me. And I think
that in the future the businesses that
set up a culture that encourage people
to learn AI build fast responsibly um
talk to customers would drive a lot more
value than the more hierarchical silo
organizations.
>> Yeah, it it starts with hiring the right
people and then nurturing this in your
organization. When you say learn how to
use AI and become proficient with AI,
can you give me some benchmarks like of
a person who's like say a marketer,
knowledge worker, advanced with AI, what
are you looking for when you're
interviewing this person?
>> I'm pretty sure my team's ahead of the
curve. All of my marketers know how to
code. So, as part of how I interview
marketers, we ask them what they've
built and uh if they have not built any
software.
>> If it's a dashboard, is it good or bad?
Like, is it too basic or
>> a dashboard? Again, my team's probably,
you know, somewhat ahead of the curve,
but uh
>> was good to hear like that.
>> All of my marketers have built much
specific things in
>> Oh, I I feel like um I don't know the
other day uh one of our someone on the
marketing team was talking about the
tools that he had built to uh when he's
considering writing an article on
something, it will um crawl the web,
find related work, has a custom desktop
app, actually built a desktop app that
runs on his Mac to um highlight related
articles for him. then you can chat to
the whole system navigate you know the
thing he's writing as well as the
related work and he had a large
dashboard for trolling the internet to
highlight to him exciting things that
are popping up um now even on my team I
think that marketers is ahead of the
curve
>> but that's that's great to hear any
other interesting use cases uh that will
inspire people to build something
similar
>> let's see maybe u uh my finance team
uses AI extensively
So I think uh uh my um one of my CFOs uh
realized that you know her team was
spending hours every week clicking
through documents open this copy paste
this number here and so um she started
building uh automation scripts that runs
on a routine that um automatically opens
files checks what's in there checks for
consistency highlights to her team if
there's something uh if there's
something they need to be paying
attention to if a new document has
showed up. So I find that rather than
waiting around for an engineer to do the
work for them, the team's ability to to
kind of a not just build dashboards but
build kind of a data management
infrastructures. They can ingest data,
alert them if something's happening.
>> I think uh my finance and marketing
teams are doing that. Oh my recruiting
team um well we actually have recruiting
engineers which are really professional
engineers that sit in a recruiting team
that are building very sophisticated
tools for recruiting. And this is
actually the other trend. I think
marketers, recruiters, HR professional,
ops people should all learn AI. But the
other thing is when you take an engineer
and embed them in these teams, then that
further accelerates what you can do.
>> We do the same. We we start with
something basic, build it ourselves,
then we hit the wall, an engineer comes
in, we build it further.
>> Frankly, when you look at not just
software engineers, but recruiting
engineers, marketing engineers, HR
engineers, I think there's so much
valuable engineering work that can now
be done. I'm just, you know, not worried
about running out of, [laughter]
frankly, all my friends were so busy. We
think, boy, how could we run out of
engineering jobs?
>> Yeah. Yeah. There are so many cool ideas
you can experiment on. But you touched
up on something that is actually one of
the fears when when we talk about like
financial information, how much you're
giving to AI. So, I gave my perplexity
permission to scan my Fidelity account
so it can track my portfolio, tell me
when to rebalance. It doesn't do
anything on my behalf, but it has
access. Do you think there is any
problem with that?
>> This is complicated. I think AI and
privacy is a complex area. Um, and it
depends a lot on the company that you
are sharing your data with. So, for
example, I trust all the hyperscalers to
really 100%, you know, follow their
terms of service and to do what they
say. my personal opinion not not giving
legal business advice but I'd be shocked
if you know the largest hyperscalers
publish the terms of service with some
privacy notice and if they breach that
because that would be not the culture be
so damaging of the long-term business
model now that's on the largest
hyperscaler side if you look at AI
company's side there's been you know at
least one company that I won't name that
seems to occasionally change the terms
of service and if you're using it you go
to the website so you pop up hey we
changed the terms of service to retain
your data or train your data and if
you're aren't paying attention and click
the wrong button then they suddenly gave
themselves permission to access your
data in a way that I'm not that
comfortable with. I feel like I handle
you know some sensitive information. So
then I tend to be very careful with the
businesses that I just don't feel that
culture and the DNA and frankly the
long-term business model is as tied to
protecting individual user privacy than
the hyperscalers. And um I see
businesses, you know, get this as well.
For example, one of my teams, AI Aspire,
we work with very large corporations,
including banks, with incredibly
sensitive financial data. And as you can
imagine, AI Aspire and our and our
clients do not willy-nilly share, you
know, really sensitive I often material
nonpublic information, right? NPI uh
with Frontier with with Frontier Labs
without really careful thinking about
the guardrails and privacy. So I think
it's complicated.
>> So trusting hypers scale, but also u
another thing that you can do, you can
download an open source model and just
run it on your computer and then it just
stays on your computer, right?
>> Yes. I think yes I it turns out a lot of
banks will actually run um the things in
uh you know a virtual private car or on
prem so they so it never even leaves
their control but I think for
individuals it's true for for the really
sensitive things um uh I sometimes run a
local model and it's been interesting
with the open way models some of the
latest open way models are approaching
frontier capability and that are you
know actually small enough they're
actually really good models now they can
run on it
>> yeah the one from Meta right the recent
one
>> oh yes Metamuse is a good model and I'm
thinking Also the latest version of Quen
is also very good but I think frankly
these models change every other week. So
I think the best practice is to not get
stuck on one but keep on trying new
models.
>> So basically when there is a situation
that you don't trust anyone you run a
local model and this is how you keep
your data safe.
>> I do trust the hyperscalers but
sometimes for you know literally NMPI
material nonpublic information that I
won't even send to that I just can't
even send that to the cloud. So that uh
I'll either do it manually without AI
help or if I really need to use AI then
you know really carefully only use a
local model.
>> Interesting. Okay. This is this is this
is an interesting one. Okay. What about
loss of human control over AI? Because
I've talked to I talked to Yoshua Benja
who is very um negative when it comes to
open free AI without any regulation and
he painted me some very scary pictures
of AI taking over control because we
basically the the whole scenario is we
can't control something that's smarter
than us and if AI gets smarter and
smarter where where do we end up? What
do you think about that? I think about
something else that we can't control
which is um airplanes. No one can build
an airplane that you can fly perfectly.
Winds will buffet it around. And then
candly in the early days of developing
airplanes, some airplanes crash and
people died and it was tragic and awful.
But through the early lessons learned,
we then learned to control airplanes
better and better. So that today, you
know, we can mostly get in an airplane
and not fear too much for our lives. And
it's really like that too of AI. No one
can perfectly control AI because it
generates tokens or outputs that a
little bit random. So we don't really
know what exactly it'll do. But as we
run them and you know there's been a
small number of mishaps which is
unfortunate and some number of mishaps
have done some real damage but the way
we engineer almost any system from an
airplane to electric circus to now AI is
carefully grow their capabilities so
that we can have a controlled
environment in which to measure what's
wrong and then to shape it to make sure
we can control it well enough that it
behaves responsibly and safely and to
this day we can't perfectly control any
airplane and we will never perfectly
control AI either but I think um we are
certainly controlling them well enough
that this loss of control doesn't feel
like science science
>> fiction yeah what about deep fakes
>> deep fakes are a problem well one of the
most disgusting things I've ever seen or
heard of is non-consensual
intimate deep fake imagery
>> I'm really glad that you know US
Congress has been moving Right. Let's
pass laws. Get rid of that. Penalties
for that. I'm just I think there's some
really problematic uses of AI that we
should outlaw, heavily penalize. Let's
just get rid of that.
>> What do you think about children and
social connection when it comes to AI
with kids using more of AI? Because
we've seen social media how, you know,
there are people who are dumb scrolling
all day and my daughter who is 5 years
old now, whenever I don't have an
answer, he's like, "Ask Chad GPT." And
like, who's that person? I'm like, "I
don't know. Ask Jajiv Viti like she
thinks Jaji knows everything. What would
you say about you know kids future with
AI?
>> First I think kids have a bright future.
It's just such an exciting time to be
child to grow up in this environment
with tools that none of us ever had
before. [gasps] At the same time we've
seen that social media um I think social
media has probably been blamed a bit
more than it deserves. But it does
deserve blame uh has kind of not been
great for kids. I actually worry a lot
about it's a wonderful tool, but AI
damaging learning is something I worry a
lot about. So, it turns out um I have a
5-year-old and a seven-year-old. When I
teach them math, they're so young enough
that I can basically, you know, not let
them use a calculator, can say, "How do
you multiply these numbers?" And I don't
give them a calculator and practice that
with them. But as they're a little bit
older, I worry a lot about students
using cognitive offloading to AI in a
way that damages the long-term learning
retention. Um, but then at the same
time, oh, I actually built an app. I did
not like any of the, you know, free
online learning to type types of things.
So, I actually built my own to um have
my daughter learn to type. And I'm
hoping that she's actually getting
pretty decent now for a seven-year-old.
>> Oh, she's Oh, yeah. She actually typed
all the lowercase letters. she's a
little bit fit, you know, not her shift
uppercase letter is a little bit not
quite there. But I think that this um
unlocks, you know, responsible adult
supervised use of online tools and I
think it's really tricky. You know, I
think um adult supervised use of digital
tools seems a great thing for kids, but
too many adults don't have time to
supervise the use of the tools and then
the incentives of [gasps] say social
media, right, to do funny things.
>> Yeah. has to be the right incentive when
it comes to AI. Okay. [snorts] You
mentioned we we talked about the fears.
We talked about how you can improve your
work with AI. Can you name some of the
biggest opportunities in AI in 2026 for
people who want to build? for an
individual that wants to build. I don't
think it's one size fits all, but
because the cost of building has
plummeted,
um, [clears throat]
I encourage people to learn AI, build
fast, and talk to customers. I find
myself building things, I don't know,
every week, every weekend because I or
someone on our team, we have some
problem and I have some idea for
building some AI thing. to automate it.
Last weekend, I had really I was using a
frontier model to analyze a lot of our
key business metrics because I didn't
have time to do it myself, but it was
kind of measuring, you know, deandized
key business metrics and I didn't have
time to go find a data scientist to go
work me on it. So, I just did variety of
frontier models being really careful on
their uh data retention policies. I did
not use models with data retention
policies I don't like uh in order to
analyze data. But and then I find that
um what's happen of AI is the cost of
building has plummeted and so the
challenge is shifting to deciding what
to build which I was calling which I've
been calling the product management
bottleneck and so people you know
founders engineers product managers that
can talk to customers get a sense for
the taste of judgment on what to build
and then build with AI and iterate
quickly. I think that's just a ton of
exciting things to do
>> and you've been starting so many
companies. You're like when I looked at
your portfolio, do you think for
beginners when you said you built
something during the weekend, how do you
decide what to focus on or you can
pursue multiple ideas because of AI now
and you can just be, you know, playing
in different companies at the same time.
>> It turns out building a company is still
really, really hard and so there's a lot
to be said for a single threaded
leadership or someone that's fully
focused on just one thing. I find it,
you know, over a weekend I can often
build an Elm wrap, build a simple
application, but I wish it was that easy
to build a large company. Um, I find
that building something meaningful often
takes either real technical depth uh and
or deep customer insight and integration
with customers. And yes, we can now, you
know, use AI to code something in a few
hours, but that's a small piece of the
puzzle. So spending time understanding
the technical complexity and building
the really complex software that takes
us like months you know maybe years or
having that deep custom insight to
decide what to build that also just
takes a lot talking to people reading
facial expressions surveys doing that
over and over until we figure out what
to build. Um and so I think sometimes
there's a lot of value to sampling
widely but then having that focus for an
individual to go really deep in a couple
sectors that that still seems important
for building a business. My last
question, I know it's we don't have much
time, but I wanted to ask you about AGI
just because people use this word so
much and some people say I think Jensen
Hang said we already reached AGI. You
said it's decades away. What's the one
criteria when you're going to say we
reach AGI?
>> So different people say we reach AGI at
different times because of different
definitions of AGI. The definition I'm
most familiar with is AI that could do
any intellectual task that a human can.
But so the human brain can take say five
years to study and do a PhD thesis or or
and so can AI write a PhD thesis or a
human can learn to drive a truck through
a dense rainforest with you know tens of
minutes of practice. So when can AI do
that to drive new environment with tens
of minutes of practice. It feels like
there's a long list of these things that
AI cannot do uh for what feels to me
decades. I hope it's only decades. maybe
you turn out to be longer. So that's why
I think for that definition of AI or
AGI, AGI is still very far away.
>> But um it turns out because of you know
economic incentives, I think open
Microsoft had an agreement that's
actually been renegotiated now. So
that's gone away. But open AI had an
economic incentive to try to declare
reaching AGI earlier. Uh and so it turns
out that if you come up with other
definitions of AI depending on how far
you lower the bar then you could totally
have reached AGI you know already or
even 30 years ago depending on how you
want to define it.
>> Yeah true Andrew thank you so much for
this positive conversation very
applicable. I like when u you watch
something and then you go and you
measure yourself against what people are
doing with AI look at your process and
uh maybe expand it. So thank you so much
for showing what your team is doing and
thank you for your insights. Yeah, I
think given the huge benefits of AI to
come, I hope whoever was watching this
is motivated to really go learn AI,
apply it, um, and and even to go build
some